<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>EatMeatandHODL</title>
    <description>A blog about my journey in a carnivore lifestyle.</description>
    <link>https://www.eatmeatandhodl.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://www.eatmeatandhodl.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Wed, 04 Sep 2019 15:59:57 -0500</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 04 Sep 2019 15:59:57 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.8.6</generator>
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Staying Carnivore while travelling</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt; It is possible to stay on plan.&lt;p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am currently on vacation and realize that I haven't posted in a while. First, let's talk about some food options. The first leg of the trip my friend and I drove about 2000 miles. Now, you're going to get hungry during that time and not going to want to stop for a steak each time. Well, I would love to stop for a steak each time, but time and money wouldn't allow that.&lt;p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the two things we packed were dried parmesan crisps from Sam's Club. Now, I really need to cut dairy out but it was a convienent way to have something if we didn't want to stop. I also packed some Country Archer beef sticks, which I find to be the best option of beef sticks since they don't have the additives like most. Neither of them needed refigeration and I was good with that. But let's be honest, you just don't fill up on cheese crisps and beef sticks. So two good places to stop or go through the drive through are Wendy's and McDonald's.&lt;p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you go to McDonald's ask to order the quarter pound beef patty from the Alacarte menu. They range in price depending on which one you go to. The most I have paid is there is $1.69 a patty. Now, these do in a pinch but I find them to have a funny taste. The top is usually cooked well but the bottom is soggy. I have found I much prefer the taste of Wendy's. Just tell them you want to order plain large beef patties. They are cooked thouroughly and much more tasty. My guess is becasue they don't freeze their patties like McDonald's does. Something to note with Wendy's is that if you don't ask them to put the patties all in one container, you will get them all individually in a plastic box. I learned this the hard way.&lt;p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My friend has his dog on a carnivore way of eating as well, so this was great for us.I ordered some patties for all of us, including the dog. Very convienent and we didn't have to put him on kibble for trip. Now of course you can stop and eat at about most restaurants, just order meat without the sides. I always get funny looks and they keep asking if I want sides, but generally most places will accomodate. Some will even give you a discounted price, but some won't. You just have to be prepared to pay full price but happy if they give one. As far as Wendy's pricing goes, the most I have paid is $1.59 a patty. It generally takes three of them to fill me up, but if I am ravenous, I can do four. That's a pretty cheap meal. I do recommend keeping some salt with you. I always need to add some.&lt;p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One other thing you are going to run into is people that are not carnivore still follow traditional eating habits. Meaning they don't understand that you need more meat to fill up. They will give you a small cut of meat just like they have, but then they have all the sides so they are full. You have to speak up and explain it to them.&lt;p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So you can stay carnivore while travelling, you just have to plan ahead, and speak up. I flew home instead of driving. At the airport I was able to find a bbq joint and they gave me a discount for ordering just the meat. Score! The best part of the flight home was that I had so much extra room with the seatbelt. This way of eating is truly healing me and making my life so much better. To those of you who might be travelling soon, you can still stick to it! I have confidence in you. &lt;p&gt;


&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt; It is possible to stay on plan.&lt;p&gt;

&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        
        <pubDate>Thu, 20 Jun 2019 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.eatmeatandhodl.com/blog/Travel/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.eatmeatandhodl.com/blog/Travel/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Six Month Mark</title>
        <description>&lt;div class=&quot;post&quot;&gt;&lt;h2 class=&quot;pageTitle&quot;&gt;Six Month Mark&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/6monthmark.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt; This is way overdue and I know it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; I am officially at the six month mark. I have been quiet for a few reasons, one life has been very hectic and two, my weight loss stalled. For over a month my weight fluctuated between the same three pounds. I know this way of eating is not specifically for weight loss, but rather overall health. But, sometimes it can be disheartening. The nice thing is that people are still telling me that I look smaller and smaller, so I am happy about that. I am still proud of myself for not giving in to temptation as well. I did have one vodka shot and one glass of red wine at a celebration, but I have passed up on all the offers of sweets and catered meals offered to me. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; Here is what happened last week between a coworker and myself:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; Coworker: You have to try one of these almonds wrapped in white chocolate and lemon sugar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; Me: No thank you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; Coworker: Just one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; Me: No thanks. I have been doing great on my new eating plan.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; Coworker: No one will know. It’s just one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; Me: No. Stop asking me. I will know and I don’t want to jeopardize how far I have come.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; He hasn’t offered me anything else since that conversation. 
What I can report other than the weight stall is that my knees still feel amazing. I am still sleeping soundly and I need less of it. I am also not cringing when people want to take photos with me in them. I went out with friends last night and several of them wanted to take a group selfie. They sent me the picture and I was actually pleased with it and less critical of myself. I look like I have a neck again and my chin is more defined. Happy Dance!!
&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
        
          <description>&lt;div class=&quot;post&quot;&gt;&lt;h2 class=&quot;pageTitle&quot;&gt;Six Month Mark&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
        
        <pubDate>Thu, 11 Apr 2019 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.eatmeatandhodl.com/blog/6monthmark/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.eatmeatandhodl.com/blog/6monthmark/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Four Months Complete</title>
        <description>&lt;div class=&quot;post&quot;&gt;&lt;h2 class=&quot;pageTitle&quot;&gt;Four Months Complete&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I know I have been a little quiet the last month. I have had a lot going on and a few days I have felt a little down at times. However, I have stayed on plan and made it to four months. I am a few days past it actually. My total weight loss is at 47 pounds. I had hoped to be further than this, but it’s still a lot of weight I am no longer carrying. One day I spent 11 hours helping friends load and unload moving trucks and realized my knees did not hurt once. I don’t have a picture to attach to this post because my friend that was acting as my photographer moved away, but I will have one for my five month mark.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During this last month I have had some emotional down days. There have been many things going on and sometimes they can seem overwhelming. This is when the cravings hit hard. Even when I wasn’t hungry my brain kept saying “just have a small treat. It will make you feel better. You won’t gain it all back with just a few bites.” I even had a dream that I went to dinner with family and ate an entire chocolate and peanut butter pie. That isn’t even something I would pick, but my old demons were haunting me. I woke up feeling guilty as heck but so glad it was just a dream.  I did incorporate cheese three times as a small treat. Cheese is allowed on this plan, but it hinders me. All three times, I got sick. It was odd. I woke up in the middle of the night with stomach pain and the need to throw up. So cheese will no long be a treat for me. My body likes meat only.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have been drinking Tazo Lemon Loaf herbal tea. It is a little like dessert, but not overly sweet. It gives me a sense of having a treat without stalling me. I also signed up for Healthy Wage. It’s a website that allows you to bet on yourself to earn money for losing weight. You calculate how much you want to wager each month and how much you want to lose. They then tell you how much you can earn if you hit your goal. Of course if you don’t hit the mark, you lose the money you wagered. If I meet my goal, which I did set a bit high, I will gain $850 dollars from them. Money is a great incentive to keep at this. I will let you know if I make it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

</description>
        
          <description>&lt;div class=&quot;post&quot;&gt;&lt;h2 class=&quot;pageTitle&quot;&gt;Four Months Complete&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
        
        <pubDate>Mon, 18 Feb 2019 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.eatmeatandhodl.com/blog/fourmonths/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.eatmeatandhodl.com/blog/fourmonths/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Grease Stains</title>
        <description>&lt;div class=&quot;post&quot;&gt;

&lt;h2 class=&quot;pageTitle&quot;&gt;Carnivores understand&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Y’all. I am so excited to tell you about this. Over Christmas, I was chomping down on a juicy ribeye. Being the graceful person I am, of course I drip some of the juice down the front of my shirt. I loved that shirt too. I treated it with shout and crossed my fingers. After washing and drying it the stain was still there. I was bummed and decided to keep it as an around the house shirt. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was recently on Amazon shopping for laundry detergent (I despise going to the store). While browsing a link for a stain remover showed up in my feed. I thought why not try it? Amazon will take it back if I don’t like it. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The day I received it I got my shirt out and sprayed the stain. I let it sit for two days and then washed and dried it again. Amazing. The stain was gone! I can wear the shirt again. Woo hoo!
Here is the link if you would like to check it out:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;
&lt;iframe style=&quot;width:120px;height:240px;&quot; marginwidth=&quot;0&quot; marginheight=&quot;0&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;//ws-na.amazon-adsystem.com/widgets/q?ServiceVersion=20070822&amp;amp;OneJS=1&amp;amp;Operation=GetAdHtml&amp;amp;MarketPlace=US&amp;amp;source=ac&amp;amp;ref=tf_til&amp;amp;ad_type=product_link&amp;amp;tracking_id=eatmeatandhod-20&amp;amp;marketplace=amazon&amp;amp;region=US&amp;amp;placement=B00ISDMQ8U&amp;amp;asins=B00ISDMQ8U&amp;amp;linkId=17fbaa826e532bed5c556ce0ce079be7&amp;amp;show_border=false&amp;amp;link_opens_in_new_window=true&amp;amp;price_color=333333&amp;amp;title_color=0066c0&amp;amp;bg_color=ffffff&quot;&gt;
    &lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I will be keeping this on hand as I know this is not the last time I get grease on my outfits.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
        
          <description>&lt;div class=&quot;post&quot;&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
        
        <pubDate>Tue, 15 Jan 2019 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.eatmeatandhodl.com/blog/greasestains/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.eatmeatandhodl.com/blog/greasestains/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>90 Days Complete</title>
        <description>&lt;div class=&quot;post&quot;&gt;&lt;h2 class=&quot;pageTitle&quot;&gt;90 days&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/90days.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt; The above picture, that's my 60 day mark to 90 days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s amazing how some days it feels like this is creeping by and other days I blink and a week has passed. I remember thinking just make it through today, and then make it through this week. Now it’s become the norm and I don’t have to focus on daily struggles. That’s not to say there aren’t temptations, but it’s getting so much easier to resist. I am down a total of 38 pounds, most of which I lost in the first two months. However, I did incorporate dairy and coffee in over Christmas so I knew I would stall. That is the great thing about this way of eating. You do truly learn to listen to your body. I know that even though I love both of those, they affect me negatively. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My body shape is still changing even if I am not losing weight as fast. My pants are getting lose and several of my shirts are now sleep shirts since they are too big. 
I have incorporated exercise as well. I bought a five pound kettlebell for strength training. I know it sounds like I’m a weakling, but do a full body workout with one of those for yourself. It will work you. I am also trying to walk a mile a day. Somedays are better than others but I can feel the muscles again. 
I am so glad I decided to get back on this and push through. I can’t wait to see what another 30 days brings.&lt;/p&gt;
 
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
        
          <description>&lt;div class=&quot;post&quot;&gt;&lt;h2 class=&quot;pageTitle&quot;&gt;90 days&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
        
        <pubDate>Tue, 15 Jan 2019 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.eatmeatandhodl.com/blog/90daymark/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.eatmeatandhodl.com/blog/90daymark/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Post holidays follow up</title>
        <description>&lt;div class=&quot;post&quot;&gt;&lt;h2 class=&quot;pageTitle&quot;&gt;Happy New Year, everyone! I made it through the holidays.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am currently crashing at a friend’s house waiting for the weather to clear. I was supposed to fly out early this morning to head home, but Mother Nature had other ideas. What better time to do a recap of my travels and food temptations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So for the most part, it was easy to stay on plan. There was a bowl of nuts sitting on the counter that tempted me multiple times, but I stayed strong. Some cousins brought some goodies over, but I have that mindset right now that I have to make a change or that one cheat will lead to another year of me giving in and staying obese. My family did have lots of meat for me and no one pressured me. They did mention to make sure to drink plenty of water because they were concerned about my kidneys. I smiled and reassured them I was.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I did allow myself five cups of coffee with heavy cream and some cheese over the course of almost two weeks. This was my “cheat” for the holidays, even though most carnivores allow it on a daily basis. While it is perfectly fine for others, I have learned it’s not for me. It caused some bloating and constipation. I also realized I have an addiction to cheese. Once I started having some, I found it harder and harder to say no, or not grab some when I was watching movies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By having these, I fell into my old ways of just eating because it’s breakfast time or because it was there. I wasn’t listening to my body. Coffee with butter or cream definitely interrupts my appetite triggers. So it’s back off coffee and dairy for me. As much as I love them, I love me more and have to push through this. I am not going to regret eating anything. It’s all part of learning to listen to your body. However, next year I plan to stick to my meat only plan. I don’t need cheats to be happy; spending time with those I love is what I need.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cheers to a New Year and continuing to improve health. Stay strong everyone. We can do this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
        
          <description>&lt;div class=&quot;post&quot;&gt;&lt;h2 class=&quot;pageTitle&quot;&gt;Happy New Year, everyone! I made it through the holidays.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
        
        <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.eatmeatandhodl.com/blog/holidaysdone/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.eatmeatandhodl.com/blog/holidaysdone/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Surviving the holidays</title>
        <description>&lt;h2 class=&quot;pageTitle&quot;&gt;We can overcome this&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;post&quot;&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many people can’t understand why I chose to start this right before the holidays. A lot of them have said to wait and start in the New Year. However, for me it’s a now or never situation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yes, the holidays can be crippling for any person trying to eat healthy. Everywhere you turn, there is sugar. People are baking as if it’s the end of the world. Commercials show these super happy skinny people eating a chocolate bar or cakes. This year I had a student bring me a plate of homemade cookies, I received chocolate truffles, and candy canes as gifts and I travelled home, where I fell off the wagon last year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had to put myself in the mindset that no matter how good those things taste, my health and weight have to come first. Do I want the cookies, or do I want my joints to continue to heal? Being on this way of eating for just over 60 days is helping tremendously. The more you stay strong the easier it becomes to turn away from the temptations. I thanked the people that gave me the goodies as gifts, but immediately gave them to others to eat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In my mind going to the grocers during the holidays is the equivalent of having multiple drug dealers in one place offering every addiction you have right at your fingertips. There are Christmas goodies everywhere and the smell of spices are overpowering. You just want to dig into that gingerbread cake and have that pumpkin latte. I walk right to the meat section and then to the register trying to avoid it all. But, even there you aren’t safe. The bags of cocoa and chocolates line the lanes. In order to help combat the temptation, either I get on my phone to read something and distract myself, or I do this slight bend at the knees repeatedly to remind myself that it used to be painful when I did that while eating junk food. It seems to help a lot. If you have another trick that works, please share.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I let people back home know that I am doing this and I want to stay on it through the trip. Luckily, I have a great group of friends and family. They may not understand why I am doing this, but they stocked up on meat and aren’t keeping goodies out on the counter. They will have sides to a meal but I can pass those up much easier. I will allow myself a small amount of coffee through the days but I know with it comes some consequences. When I go to others homes to visit I know there will be so much to overcome, but I have to make the change now, or I never will.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are just starting on this and you are struggling, know that you are not alone. Ask those in your life for support even if they don’t agree with it. If they argue just smile and know that you are bettering yourself and it’s worth it. (If you’re like me it’s also a little satisfying to prove them wrong in the long run.) Find an online group that you can turn to or even give me a shout on twitter [@eatmeatandhodl](https://twitter.com/EatMeatandHODL?lang=en)  I will give you support as much as I can.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am going to take a small break from writing over the next week so I can focus on my family and friends. But, I will be back in the New Year to let you know how the rest of my trip unfolds. I wish all of you a Happy Christmas and New Year!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
        
          <description>&lt;h2 class=&quot;pageTitle&quot;&gt;We can overcome this&lt;/h2&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Sat, 22 Dec 2018 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.eatmeatandhodl.com/blog/survivingtheholidays/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.eatmeatandhodl.com/blog/survivingtheholidays/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>TSA</title>
        <description>&lt;h2 class=&quot;pageTitle&quot;&gt;The violating screening&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;post&quot;&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;It’s 5 am in the morning and I just went through TSA so I can fly home for Christmas. I am sure you are wondering why this would be relevant to a carnivore lifestyle. You see I generally fly a couple times a year and every time I go through the violating process of screening, my left knee always sets off the scanning area. I always get the extra pat down and sometimes they lift my pant leg to inspect it. I mentioned earlier in one of my blogs that my knee pain is gone. Going through the body scanner this morning was like a free little health check. I was clear of any targeted areas. For the first time my left knee wasn’t cause of suspicion. No pat down or pulling my pant leg up. Hallelujah.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;While I still am vehemently against the TSA it seems that eating like a carnivore is going to at least ease the process for me. This is just another reason for me to stay on this way of eating.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
        
          <description>&lt;h2 class=&quot;pageTitle&quot;&gt;The violating screening&lt;/h2&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Fri, 21 Dec 2018 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.eatmeatandhodl.com/blog/tsa/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.eatmeatandhodl.com/blog/tsa/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>OMAD</title>
        <description>&lt;h2 class=&quot;pageTitle&quot;&gt;One Meal A Day&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;post&quot;&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;In the world of social media, there are tons and tons of acronyms for everything. The diet world is no exception.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;I stumbled across the OMAD term multiple times and was curious what it meant. I finally had to ask one of the groups. Here it is: One Meal A Day. That was simple. I started reading people’s comments and reasons for doing it. My understanding is that you end up fasting for 24 hours in between each meal. Fasting is a sensitive subject in the Facebook world of carnivores and zero carbers. I understand both sides of the argument and will write about it on another day.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;Back to the OMAD topic. I decided to try it to see how it affected my body and mental clarity. I started on a Friday and only ate lunch. I was definitely hungry by the time 1pm came around. I was able to skip dinner completely without any hunger. In fact, I didn’t experience hunger until around 2pm the next day. I ate until I was full and noticed again that I wasn’t hungry at dinner time. This continued on the rest of the week. The interesting part of this is that when I get home from work every day the first thing I do, is start cooking. It’s always been engrained in us that you have to eat three meals a day or five small ones to be healthy. Part of being carnivore is realizing that you have learn to eat when hungry. I thought I was doing that, but I was still clearly following eating patterns I had learned my entire life. OMAD was simple to follow and I was eating enough meat that I wasn’t hungry on the off hours. I decided to continue with it. I noticed on day 8 I didn’t eat enough at my meal and had to have some dinner that evening.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;I am no longer on the OMAD plan, but I am trying to truly listen to my body. Today I have only eaten one meal and I feel sated. My mental clarity remained constant throughout the trial and I even went for some long walks on those days without feeling famished. I don’t plan to do this again, but it really helped me learn to listen to my body.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
        
          <description>&lt;h2 class=&quot;pageTitle&quot;&gt;One Meal A Day&lt;/h2&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Sat, 15 Dec 2018 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.eatmeatandhodl.com/blog/omad/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.eatmeatandhodl.com/blog/omad/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>60 Days Complete</title>
        <description>&lt;div class=&quot;post&quot;&gt;&lt;h2 class=&quot;pageTitle&quot;&gt;Before and After&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/60dayphoto.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;The above picture, that’s what a 60 day difference makes.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;When I started this, I put myself on a short timeline to see if I could do it. I told myself if I could make it to twenty days, I would be able truly take it and run with it. I decided to start right before Halloween, the best holiday ever. There was candy everywhere. Lord help me I wanted to dive into the Reese’s cups. Every person at work seemed to have a candy dish out to tempt me. However, I pushed through and made it to 20 days. After thirty days, I felt like I was starting to gain even more control. I won’t lie and say I’m not tempted, but I certainly find it easier to say no. Sweets have always been my downfall. On a low carb plan you still get to have them, so I couldn’t break the addiction. I was just using artificial sweetener instead of real sugar to feed it. With the carnivore way of eating, you don’t keep feeding the addiction. You learn to fuel your body when it needs it.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;There have been several noticeable changes I would like to share with you. I am down 32 pounds! Join me in a happy dance.  Of course, weight loss is my main goal, but there are a few others I found just as important that are worth talking about. For the first time I am learning to listen to my body. I know when I am truly hungry vs just eating because there is food available.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;I also want to talk about joints. My knees used to grind and pop constantly. If you were near me when walking up a flight of stairs, you could audibly hear them grind. This was pointed out by a friend one day when he said “Is that your knees?!”. Now I no longer have any grinding noises or popping. They no longer hurt when I lay in bed at night. That is a huge deal for me. I once watched a knee replacement surgery and I knew I never wanted to have that done. I believe staying on this way of eating will mean I never need one.&lt;/p&gt;
    
    &lt;p&gt;Another thing that I find intriguing is that floater in my left eye is gone. If you have ever had floaters, you know how annoying they are. I no longer have that gray spot in the way of my vision. I didn’t expect that to happen but I am quite happy it has.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;I would say these first 60 days have been truly beneficial. I can’t wait to report back to you in another 60 days to see what has transpired. Stay tuned.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
        
          <description>&lt;div class=&quot;post&quot;&gt;&lt;h2 class=&quot;pageTitle&quot;&gt;Before and After&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
        
        <pubDate>Mon, 10 Dec 2018 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>https://www.eatmeatandhodl.com/blog/sixtydaymark/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.eatmeatandhodl.com/blog/sixtydaymark/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
      
    
  </channel>
</rss>